<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundi Willy&#39;s Autonomous Vehicles Workshop</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fundi Willy&#39;s Autonomous Vehicles Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:01:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving All Content Here - Consolidating</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/moving/</guid>
      <description>For a while since I have had an interest in autonomous vehicles, I have been writing my content accross various platforms. These include:
 Medium Githuka.com Twitter  While this is good for diversification, its not good especially when making a follow-up on progress, or when I want to check up on a previous code sinpet or photo.
Just too inefficient from my point of view.
Due to this I shall be moving all my content to here autonomy so that I can ensure streamlining of my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Good Old C</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/good_old_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/good_old_c/</guid>
      <description>Autonomous vehicle systems is all about hardware interraction with software and the algorithims that go well with it. For this, to be a good technician/engineer one must master the relevant software and hardware tools that are required for this.
All through the Udacity&amp;rsquo;s course for Self Driving Cars the language that I used mostly was C++. I also used Python for mostly high level programming like Neural networks and Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time To Get Moving — My First Autonomous Car Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blog/first_car_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 08:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/blog/first_car_project/</guid>
      <description>The Python study program is over, am so excited to get my hands working on something. Last year I got a Red Hammer H2 RC Car. This car is made in China 1:14 and runs on 5x1.5V .I want to learn how to make it drive itself. Am sure there are tutorials online but I wanna make my own version . Currently it is controlled by a remote and has good suspension kits installed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>