<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundi Willy&#39;s Autonomous Vehicles Workshop</title>
    <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fundi Willy&#39;s Autonomous Vehicles Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:11:33 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://autonomy.githuka.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Update&#43;Fuse Blown Weekend</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/radio_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:11:33 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/radio_update/</guid>
      <description>GoodMorning, I hope this post finds you well, and I hope you had a great weekend.
This past weekend I have been busy wiring up the radio and moving it from the dashboard to the back. I find it more practical since I don&amp;rsquo;t interract with it so much during driving, furthermore the front section is currently occupied by the tablet mod.
The SONY radio has the following sets of inputs and outputs:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi&#43;Webcam Based Dashcam</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/dashcam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 09:06:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/dashcam/</guid>
      <description>Its time for my car to have eyes. It needs to see the road ahead.
One of the main cimponents of a connected autonomous vehicle is the ability to percieve its environment. This is made possible by sensors and cameras. This is the main difference between Waymo and Tesla.
I have a Raspberry Pi which I plan to connect a desktop USB webcam to it providing the crucial vision function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Making My Carputer</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/carputer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 08:24:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/carputer/</guid>
      <description>For a while now since I got this Nissan Note I have been toying aroud with the idea of having a Carputer. A carputer is a car-computer which handles connetivity of all devices in a car. Most are aftermarket and operate on a higher level that than the ECU.
Basic Requirements of a Carputer  Computing device Screen Input method Power  Computing Device This is perhaps the most important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Battery Dashboard Status Monitor</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/voltmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 07:53:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/voltmeter/</guid>
      <description>So this weekend I have been busy adding more devices to the car.
For a while I have had the challenge of not knowing the status of the car battery and wanted if there was a way I could get to know the voltage of the battery. I can connect a multimeter but this is not convinient when driving.
My car has a normal Lead Acid Accumulator battery with a voltage of 12V at normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio Unit DIY Re-Wiring&#43;Learning</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/radio_wiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 09:09:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/radio_wiring/</guid>
      <description>As I write this post the radio is out and the front panel looks like a mess.
A peek behind the radio system last week looked like an wiring graveyard. The place was full of accumulated dust and used insulation tape everywhere. Unlabelled wires everywhere and weak connections.
Wiring I spent today cleaning and re-doing the wiring and improving the overall appearance of that place.
Dashboard situation diring working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RealDash App</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/realdash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 22:03:33 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/realdash/</guid>
      <description>Among the useful functional apps that I have added this week in the tablet is RealDash. The guys behind this project have done a wonderful job.
RealDash is simply the most beautiful dash that your car company should have installed in your car but did not. They have many designs of a digital dash together with music, trip and games.
There is a free and premium version.
The app runs smoothly on the tab but it intermittently works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vehicle Android Tablet Heads Up Display and Media Center</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/android_tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 19:11:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/android_tablet/</guid>
      <description>The internet is awash with so many in-car head up displays from so many manufaturers.
Lets face it the stock HUDs are so boring and old school, not apealing at all.
In this project I mnaged to fit an old Android Tablet in replacement of my car audio to also play music and display data from the ECU.
The data from the ECU is transmitted via a Bluetooth OBD2 device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12V 1A DC Power Source &#43; ETC Card Reader Removed</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/etc_12v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 21:07:17 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/etc_12v/</guid>
      <description>My test car is Japanese and Japanese vehicles have ETC Toll Devices. These are devices mounted on preety all Japanese cars so that when you pass a toll gate there is no need to stop, the deice will be detected automatically by a sensor on the gate and payment will be done electronically.
But when the cars leave Japan, most of these devices are no-longer useful, like here in Kenya. They are powerd by a 12V DC which comes from the battery and is turned on as soon as you turn the key to ACC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Issues That Need Fixing</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/car_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 23:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/car_issues/</guid>
      <description>The following are the issues/problems that my Nissan Note E11 has which I new before purchase of the vehicle.
 Airbag Lamp Flashing - This means that there is a problem with the airbag system but also the horn works only when the steering wheel is on a specific position. I think its a Spiral Cable Clock Spring problem. The clock spring is located between the steering wheel and the steering column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CARLA Release 0.96 on Archlinux</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/carla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 13:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/carla/</guid>
      <description>CARLA is an open source simulator for autonomous driving research.
Its the kind of tool that AI and Autonomous Driving techies can use to speed up research in a real world simulation environment.
Carla has been in development for a while now and mid last year I tried to install in on my Arch machine, it was tough.
Carla was built on Ubuntu and best runs on Ubuntu, but I dont use Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing A Good Microcontroller For The Car</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/microcontroller/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 05:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/microcontroller/</guid>
      <description>Today is a good day for science.
Yesterday I stayed up late selecting which microcontroller I will use for the car project.
Well, its not that I had a plethora of chips to choose from, but on my workshop lay two chips:
 ATmega328 STC15F2K60S2  ATMega328 Lets first look at the ATmega328 is a single-chip microcontroller more closely. It has the following features:
 8-bit RISC (Reduced Instruction Set Computer) processor core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving All Content Here - Consolidating</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/moving/</guid>
      <description>For a while since I have had an interest in autonomous vehicles, I have been writing my content accross various platforms. These include:
 Medium Githuka.com Twitter  While this is good for diversification, its not good especially when making a follow-up on progress, or when I want to check up on a previous code sinpet or photo.
Just too inefficient from my point of view.
Due to this I shall be moving all my content to here autonomy so that I can ensure streamlining of my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvtop - A Task Monitor For NVIDIA GPUs</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/nvtop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 20:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/nvtop/</guid>
      <description>Nvtop is the htop for NVIDIA GPU&amp;rsquo;s. This tool is very handy especially when you need to check the stats of the GPU as you train your neural network.
Installation yay -S nvtop  For more info, check the project&amp;rsquo;s page on Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Hardware Specs Manual</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/specs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 14:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/specs/</guid>
      <description>I thought it be good to put the specs of my local GPU so that in future, any tests that I do I can use this as a reference.
Make: NVIDIA GTX 1050 This GPU is built using NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s Pascal architecture, a successor of Maxwell which was introduced in 2016.
The GPU&amp;rsquo;s base frequency is 1354 MHz; the GPU Boost rating jumps to 1455 MHz.
Like the 1050 Ti, GeForce GTX 1050 exposes 32 ROPs and the same 1 MB of L2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Good Old C</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/good_old_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/good_old_c/</guid>
      <description>Autonomous vehicle systems is all about hardware interraction with software and the algorithims that go well with it. For this, to be a good technician/engineer one must master the relevant software and hardware tools that are required for this.
All through the Udacity&amp;rsquo;s course for Self Driving Cars the language that I used mostly was C++. I also used Python for mostly high level programming like Neural networks and Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udacity&#39;s Term 2 - Sensor Fusion, Localization and Control</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/udacity_second_term/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 01:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/udacity_second_term/</guid>
      <description>Term 2 of Udacity’s Self Driving Car Nanodegree is all about Sensor Fusion, Localization, Control and the C++math behind all the topics. I cant wait. I love math and math loves me. Term 1 was quite challenging for me in terms to time management but for this second term am all in.
In this term I cant wait to dive deeper into the Extended Kalman Filter and the Kidnapped Vehicle which really sounds deeper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udacity Self Driving Car Nanodegree-Lets Do This</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/udacity_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 07:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/udacity_start/</guid>
      <description>So much desire ends up in accomplishment. After waiting, saving and prepping(coding) for sometime I am ready to start my journey into the world of Self Driving Cars at Udacity.
I have read reviews, gone through students’ blogs on the course, tried out some projects on my own, so now I get to get my feet wet in the course.
Self-driving cars represent one of the most significant advances in modern history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time To Get Moving — My First Autonomous Car Project</title>
      <link>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/first_car_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 08:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://autonomy.githuka.com/blog/first_car_project/</guid>
      <description>The Python study program is over, am so excited to get my hands working on something. Last year I got a Red Hammer H2 RC Car. This car is made in China 1:14 and runs on 5x1.5V .I want to learn how to make it drive itself. Am sure there are tutorials online but I wanna make my own version . Currently it is controlled by a remote and has good suspension kits installed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>